okay well the Trump Administration is
said to be ready to purge the CIA the
same way it did other federal workers
now this is the same offer that other
federal government workers were offered
if you retire you'll get paid for 6 to
eight months you don't have to come to
work and then your contract ends and you
go do something else now the Wall Street
Journal reports that this move is to
quote bring the agency in line with
President Trump's priorities including
targeting drug cartels a CIA spokes work
person said that this is an effort to
Infuse the agency with Renewed Energy
but is there something more well our
next guest is the former CIA agent and a
whistleblower he says that the CIA
considers Israel an antagonistic power
to the tune of North Korea he joins us
today that thank you for joining us uh
John kyaku oh it's my pleasure thanks so
much for having me the pleasure is all
ours so do you think that this CIA Purge
is perhaps related to the Netanyahu
visit or is this something that Israel
actually
wants I don't think it has very much to
do with Israel I think it has very much
to do with Donald Trump and to tell you
the truth Donald Trump is the first
president with the guts to downsize the
CIA since the Carter Administration the
organization has just grown and grown
and it's become bloated and topheavy I
remember 20 years ago senior Cia officer
saying that it was
inexcusable that there were more CIA
officials in CIA headquarters than there
were overseas actually doing the job of
recruiting spies to steal secrets so I I
think this is a very positive
development I want to get back to the
the relationship with Israel inside the
United States in a second but right
before the break we were talking about
the media uh we've had a number of
whistleblowers on our show tell us that
if the CIA the Deep state the
intelligence Community want to get
stories out they can go to Politico they
can go to the Washington Post they go to
the New York Times that's where a lot of
these stories show up so how can the CIA
now that you know we we're outing these
news organizations like Politico today
for taking money from us Aid how can the
CIA get out their fake stories John I
know right this is scandalous it's
scandalous and it's unamerican it it
used to be a common thing for the CIA to
plant stories in the Us Media uh by
recruiting American journalists that
became illegal in 1975 and so they just
did the next best thing they just said
hey Politico hey New York Times or
Washington Post you're a patriot why
don't you put this story in your paper
for us Patriot and then they ended up
doing it there's a journalist um at
Bloomberg by the name of um Jason
Leopold who's an outstanding
investigative journalist he did a
Freedom of Information act request some
years ago asking the cia's uh office of
public affairs for all correspondents
all email correspondents between the CIA
and American journalists and what he
found was several very interesting
things first um a a major journalist at
uh at NBC and MSNBC was sending his his
reports his articles to the CIA for
clearance before he sent them to his own
editor at NBC inexcusable but even more
interestingly he found that by way is
that person's name kend delanian at NBC
person name is kendel lanan yes indeed
it is and it's black ACH I had it was
yeah but he also found he also found an
independent journalist who had written
uh to the CIA saying hey I uncovered
this important story do you have a
comment and the response from the CIA
was don't you dare report that story if
you do you are never invited to CIA
Christmas party again and we will never
confirm or deny any story for you so
they don't even have to recruit
journalists anymore they just bully them
or they say Hey listen we like you you
like us we're all friends why don't you
do this for us do you recall I think it
was last year when Claire D's talking
about her work playing a CIA agent in
what what is it home the Homeland
Homeland right she said that she had
been to some kind of intelligent camp
where the CIA was allying itself with
Hollywood and the media and coar cut her
off do you buy that absolutely yes the
CIA has long had a liaison relationship
with Hollywood Studios and just in the
last five years they created a branch
within their Bureau of public affairs uh
or office of public affairs whose job it
is solely to liaz with government with
uh the Hollywood Studios to make the CIA
look good it's exactly the same thing
that the FBI's been doing since the
40s John you know someone in our chat
just said wow I didn't know redacted was
anti-israel and of course we are not
we're just we're America First we're
pro-america and I don't want Israeli
Massad agents inside our government and
inside of our CIA well you know deeply
you've spoken out about this so I just
want to be clear we're not anti-israel
we are anti other governments inside our
government I'd love to know your
thoughts on that you've been outspoken
about how the CIA wouldn't even hold
meetings indoors because they were
worried about being bugged by Israel can
you talk about this certainly we we used
to uh meet with Israeli officials uh in
CIA headquarters all the time until the
Israelis recruited Jonathan Pard they
directed him against the American
government and he passed top secret
information back to the Israeli mad uh
in addition the Israelis were always
very kind in that they would bring gifts
when they would come to CIA headquarters
the problem is those gifts almost always
contained listening devices and were
packed with batteries so finally we had
and said look you guys this is not cool
we're not going to allow you in the
building again and so we meet with them
at an off-site facility when I first
joined the CIA like literally on my very
first day at the CIA back in January of
1990 the director of security gave all
the new employees a briefing and he said
you know there are two Israeli
intelligence officers that are declared
to the CIA and the FBI one from mosad
one from shinb it's a totally normal
common thing that happens but the FBI
was able to identify another
189 Undeclared uh Israeli Intelligence
Officers all across America spying on
the United States and trying mightily to
infiltrate American defense contractors
so look either we're going to be
brothers in this thing or we're going to
be adversaries but we can't be
both that sounds like McCarthy era I
mean is it possible that we may we now
know McCarthy was right the venona files
proved that when the fall of the Soviet
Union they gave us the proof that
McCarthy was actually looking at uh
Soviets who were infiltrated in the US
state department so is it possible now
with this new turnover of Gaza that we
do get proof that there has been Israeli
spies inside of our government too
oh we've got the proof it's just a
question of uh of releasing it and it
hasn't been in our interest over the
course of all these years uh to to
embarrass the Israelis you know spying
aside we're very very close to the
Israelis uh we give the Israelis just
about everything they want they have the
most advanced Weaponry every time we
invent something new the Israelis are
the first to get it but they're always
afraid that we're holding something back
and they just want to know for
themselves if we are holding something
back and if they find that we are
they're going to approach us and they're
going to ask us for it we're not we're
not holding anything back but this is
just the the way the Israelis operate
and the reason is and I'm not even
saying that I blame the Israelis but the
reason is um they have nowhere to go if
they're pushed anywhere it's going to be
into the Mediterranean and they can't
risk that and so they will do literally
anything to maintain their
security John yaku but you know I'll get
you out of here on this question Tulsi
gabard a lot of push back on her as it
related to Edward Snowden and you know
it's kind of amazing to me you know she
holds that he's an American hero I hold
that he's an American hero I don't know
where you come down on this but were you
surprised by the vehement and the the
vitriol from uh the questioners in that
room about Edward Snowden and her
position on that I I was actually I was
especially surprised to see it coming
from Republicans I would expect it from
Democrats and I was surprised for a
couple of
reasons and before I even I even give
you the reasons let me say I think Ed
Snowden is a Bonafide American hero and
I was proud of Tulsa gabard for standing
up for him and standing up for her own
beliefs she would not allow herself to
be bullied uh in these hearings one of
the things that bothered me the most was
the use of the word traitor there is a
constitutional definition of the word
traitor it is a person who provides Aid
and comfort to the enemy in a time of
War he did not provide Aid and comfort
to the enemy and we are not in a time of
War there has not been a declaration of
war by Congress since December the 8
1941 so he's not a traitor um one of the
other things that surprised me and I
think this came from Senator Angus King
the independent Democrat from uh from
Maine um he said that um that uh well
besides saying that that Ed Snowden
should be hanging from a tree he said
that Snowden had defected to Russia that
is absolutely not not true he was in the
transit Lounge of Moscow airport on his
way to Ecuador when John kery revoked
his passport and he was not able to fly
so let's let's keep the honest people
honest up there on Capitol
Hill that's amazing I have one more
question uh so now the Trump
Administration is saying that it's
purging the CIA because it wants to
focus more on the Western Hemisphere
than all the meddling that we've been
doing in Europe in the Middle East do
you buy
that yeah in part I think Donald Trump
has been actually pretty clear and
pretty consistent about being um
anti-war at the core of his ideology I
welcome that there's no reason why we
should always be at odds with Russia and
China if uh Marco Rubio the new
secretary of state is correct when he
says that we have to accept the
inevitability of a multi-polar world I
think that we do have to accept the EV
the inevitability of a multi-polar world
so let's let's focus on things that are
a little bit closer to home for example
Mexican drug cartels why is the CIA at
odds with the Drug Enforcement
Administration when really at the end of
the day drugs crossing the border into
the United States is a bad thing and we
should all be working together to stop
it right yeah John kiraku we appreciate
you joining us thank you for your
Insight by the way just remind our
audience here what did you blow the
whistle on specifically in the
corruption in the CIA just so our was
prosecuted for yeah I was prosecuted for
it it was I blew the whistle on the
cia's torture program in uh in 2007 and
funny enough the the Bush Administration
uh said that I hadn't done anything
wrong it was it was years later when
Barack Obama became president that the
Obama Administration prosecuted me oh
then on that on that topic what are your
I'm sorry but I'm so interested what
what are your thoughts on uh reopening
Guantanamo Bay then because I think most
of us get scared that we could then
you reopen the torture program under
Bush and Obama and have innocent people
in there so but of course there's bad
guys we do never want to see again how
do we keep an eye on that that that
doesn't turn into that yeah I I'm
strongly opposed to doing anything with
Guantanamo other than closing it and in
terms of of the bad guys pursuing the
bad guys I think really the the right
thing to do is quite simple you do what
the Constitution tells us to do you you
charge them with a crime you give them
their day in court and allow them to
face a jury of their peers if they're
guilty and we can prove that they're
guilty and then we incarcerate them but
putting them in a no man's land in a
limbo at Guantanamo isn't going to work
for anybody yeah and and what do you
think how can we know as Americans
because we didn't know what was
happening to innocent people on our tax
Dollar on our dime what do we look for
as journalists even that's a great point
and it's something that really was not
addressed for years under either George
W bush or Barack Obama you know the
answer is a difficult one for all
intensed purposes Guantanamo is off
limits for for almost all journalists
and so we have to rely on the
Congressional oversight committees but
the Congressional oversight committees
really have turned into little more than
cheerleaders for for the various
elements of the deep State well without
the oversight committees all we have
left are journalists
it makes our job that much harder all
right well let's stick with it thank you
so much for that Insight I really
appreciate pleasure thank you John great
to see you thanks so much my pleasure